So to kind of review what just happened,
because I know that was a lot.
So we went ahead and scaffolded a brand new project
using the CreateView CLI, which created
this entire Playground Directory.
And then the key thing here is that inside of our NS.html,
we can see here that we are getting our view stuff
from this source main.ts.
That's how you're going to follow this.
And so inside of main.ts, this is where we can see, ah, yes.
This is where we're mounting it to the app.
And then more importantly, that Create app, right?
If we look back at our app right here inside of Playground,
remember how we passed this object here?
This object now has been exported out into its own file.
So that's what it's talking about in terms of modularity.
So this app now, so then to continue that line of thought,
to open it here, this object that we see here
that we're exporting, this object is actually
what's being dropped in here.
So that's how those three things are being connected.
And this is also one of the reasons why build tools
can be super confusing, because there
are a lot of moving pieces to it.
And so to just sort of dive right in, get your feet wet,
what we're going to do for this exercise
is go ahead and create a brand new project with CreateView
inside of our directory that we've already been using.
And this time, you're going to rename it to whatever
your show name dash forum.
So in my case, it'll be like avatarlassairbender dash forum.
And then we're going to migrate the stuff
that we've been doing inside of index.html into app.view.
For those that haven't upgraded their Node version in a while,
if you're on anything less than 16, basically,
V doesn't play that well with some of the older versions,
because some of the modern libraries
are actually basically have moved on.
And so just so, again, this will probably
be outdated by the time, because Node moves very quickly.
But the latest stable version is actually 18 at the moment.
So it's one of those things where, if you
feel like the versions are moving quickly, don't worry,
it's not just you.
But if you're having issues with V,
please go ahead to upgrade to at least 16.
If you're having version, because I
know some people have issues with bit support, like 32 bit,
64 bit support when it comes to 18.
So something to consider if you're running into that problem.
So let's go ahead and run through that migration once more.
And this time, I'll do it with my TV show that I selected.
So let's go ahead and do this.
So what we're going to do first is
we're going to create our new app.
So I'm going to do npm create view at 3.
And the reason you want the at 3 at the moment
is because you can technically do at 2 as well.
I think at some point, there probably
will be a default version switch, so that npm create
view will do its thing.
But for now, it's always safe to just go ahead and add the 3.
So for me, my TV show is Avatar Last Airbender,
but that's a lot to type out.
So I'm just going to use the acronyms,
as most people know it, which is ATLA for Avatar the Last Airbender.
And this is the forum app for it.
For now, I'll just disable TypeScript
just because this is mainly for demo purposes.
But like I said, when it comes to any sort of app
you intend to scale, it's worth spending the time to just
configure TypeScript, add that one liner to your TS Config
to allow for JavaScript.
And once you do that, you basically
can ignore it until one day you're like, you know what?
I'm going to try types on this one file, and then easy peasy.
No, JXX.
We're not going to do worry about view router for now.
I know there were some questions regarding
a standard view project.
We will be spending time on view router.
So typically, you probably would select yes for this.
In the event you're planning to scale out your app.
But in this case, don't want to conflate the pages right now,
and it would be kind of confusing.
So no.
Same thing with Pineda for state management.
Not going to worry about testing, and for either of those.
And then the main two, I would say yes to,
is ESLint and Prettier.
That's it.
As you can see here, we have a new directory here.
And so we do ls.
We can see there you go, L-T-A-T-L-A forum.
And then if I go and change the directories into it,
we'll see now, boom, we have everything
that we would expect as far as your public directory,
your source directory that contains your app.view
component, and then all the different configuration files
and build stuff that you need.
So I'm going to go ahead and just npm install for that
and let that run.
In the meantime, we can go ahead and just migrate,
because the npm install, what it's doing
is it's allowing us to set up a local dev server, which I didn't
cover earlier, but we'll explain basically
where the benefits of it now that we're
starting to play around with it.
So let me go ahead and close all this real quick.
I need this app.view, boom, OK, split.
OK, there we go.
And then this one, we need to open up myindex.html.
And there we go.
OK, so when it comes to migration, the first thing first,
we'll notice at the top, is we did customize this title piece.
And normally, in some other build tools,
and I've experienced in the past, you
have to go through a bit of work to change that.
But it's actually fairly easy to do,
because inside of our project, you'll
notice we also have an index.html here.
And guess what?
Here is our title.
So rather than just being vtap, I'm just
going to copy over my avatar lastairbender and replace that.
There we go.
We've customized that.
Next, we have everything that's inside of this app div.
So I'm just going to go ahead and copy this,
knowing that I'm going to have a default wrapper that I'll remove.
So we'll go ahead and delete all this stuff inside of template,
because this is where our HTML is going to live.
So if I paste here, you'll see here that everything's looking good.
We have some errors that we can deal with later.
But we can go ahead and delete that id app,
because we don't need that div anymore.
Let's save that.
And then as you can see, prettier is automatically
re-indenting everything for us, which is super nice.
Then we won't worry about yelling at us at the moment.
We'll go ahead and clean up the JavaScript,
because this stuff, we're not worried about it right now.
And then we will also delete all the styles here,
because that's not relevant to us either.
OK, so finally, the last thing we need to do, though,
is we need to copy all this JavaScript that we wrote
into our script block.
So what we do that is let's take the entire object here,
cut that, and then inside of here,
we're going to export this as a default object
and just paste that in.
Nothing else has changed.
We have our entire view app now, logic-wise,
inside of here at the top.
And then the last thing we need to change here
is to add the key.
So I'm just going ahead and just do a quick dynamic key,
so bender, and then just do stat.
So for objects, it's tricky, because you don't get an index.
So I usually just end up tagging in all of the things.
So you can see here, benders, that type,
that should prevent it from duplicating.
OK, then let's just quickly do that as well.
This will be character-index, which
we will get by opening up the second argument inside
of this for list.
And then same thing for here.
So actually, this is interesting.
We have an elseif here that's doing even.
So for the sake of argument, let's just do even character
like that.
And then I can copy this.
And so inside of here, that way we basically
guarantee that even though these characters,
these things could display.
At the same time, they will have different keys.
So that way, there will be no conflict.
And then we need to actually fetch the index from this.
So let's actually split that out as well.
There we go.
Oh, looks like I have a couple more to do.
Oh gosh, there is a lot in here.
Let's call this comma list.
And then there we go.
And then vls, there are characters.
Has no adjacent if.
What?
Oh, I know why.
OK, so this is a fun error.
So I actually didn't realize this has been broken the whole time.
So this is one of the advantages of using build tools.
It's because if we look at this error message,
it says vls, vlsif has no adjacent vif, vlsif.
Because if we actually look here,
the next element right next to it, it's sibling,
is actually just a normal p element.
Through the course of me messing around, at some point,
I basically moved it way too far from its original check.
And so if we look here, this is actually where it belongs.
It actually belongs up here.
So I'm going to go ahead and cut this out.
So again, just spell check when you're writing papers
with build tools, like volar and extensions,
it can make life a lot easier to catching those kind of errors
so that you're not like, wait, where did everything go?
So these weren't caught before because the plugin just
couldn't build it?
At the time, I will say I actually had it disabled.
So if possible, it might have caught it.
But at the same time, it can be tricky sometimes
because you have to make sure you can detect
that the view language is being run.
So I'm less confident that the extension would actually
pick up on it inside of an indexed HTML.
But something worth trying later on just
to kind of see if that works.
OK, so to make sure this works, we're not
going to save the changes to this.
But this is good.
We are going to go ahead and run this, npm run def.
Here we go.
And we can see a lot of things are broken.
And the reason it's broken is because why?
Inside of our main.js, we are importing a main CSS.
And we don't want all that styles right now.
So there we go.
Now it looks exactly as we expect.
We can favorite stuff just like we did before.
Our statistics show up.
This looks good.
OK, does anyone have any questions
about the migration overall?
I know it's kind of a lot to go from the indexed HTML
to this.
But it's one of those things where I think once you get used
to it, and more importantly, most of the time
you won't be in an indexed HTML file and moving over to build,
you will basically be starting here.
And we'll basically start getting more practice
with how we work in this particular environment
going forward.
And so something else I did want to cover though,
before we move on to the next session,
is why do we go through all this process, right?
We talked a lot about build optimizations.
But one of the things that we have an advantage of when
we have a local dev server is what's
called hot module reloading.
So as we can see here, inside of app.view,
I noticed that actually my statistic doesn't have a heading.
And so in the past, when we were coding earlier,
you might have noticed I would have to add my changes.
I'd have to switch or I'd have to save it inside of VS Code.
And then I'd have to update it inside of the browser.
Well, you might have noticed that I didn't even switch context
and Veets already updated the browser
to have all my latest changes.
So that in the event, it was like, oh, stat times 2.
I can save that.
You can see it's almost super fast to the point
where sometimes you might even realize
that your code has changed.
And that's the kind of thing that Veet has done to help
as far as performance things is because now when you make
changes on your code, it's nearly instantaneous as far
as seeing the results of that.
So that has been pretty cool as far as a DevEx goes.
But in case you ever feel like this is why sometimes I make
large changes, because once again, this times 2 bit,
if you're not paying attention, you won't even
realize this updated.
So anyhow, that's something to note when it comes to working
with this.
So if you're not using Veet, you can't use the .view
way of breaking these things up?
Or is that?
Oh, you can.
Veet is just the bundler underneath.
So that's why Vue CLI allowed you to wait.
When you say break it up via the view,
you mean like via .view files?
Yeah, they have a .view file.
Oh, so that's not specific to Veet.
Webpack was able to do that too.
That's how we were doing it in Vue 2 beforehand.
So Veet is just like making the dependencies a lot faster
to load, that kind of stuff.
It actually doesn't have anything to do with Vue specifically.
OK, so the .view way of doing it is that's
you could do that with any kind of package.
OK.
And we're about to do more of that in just actually
in this section.